Summary

Apologies, but I don't summarize easily... I'm a total clown, quite literally in fact. Life is just too precious to be plagued with an overabundance of seriousness. However, that doesn't mean that I don't approach every action with careful consideration. It takes as much awareness to make someone smile as it does to diagnose a NestJS and MySQL authentication method error.

Currently I can juggle 3 balls and I am experimenting with different and creative approaches to juggling, however I can efficiently juggle many more technologies in projects utilizing stacks such as PERN, MERN, and MEAN. I can wear the makeup of a front end developer writing proper CSS for a great experience in mobile or desktop views. Or as a backend developer, coding algorithms to efficiently warehouse products as well as create APIs and applications based in React, Angular, Vue, PHP / WordPress. Having such a diverse and rich experience in tech, from system builds to administration, network architecture and administration, design, software engineering, and web development for applications affords me the comfort to work any role. Keep reading, it gets better!

Development in agile environments like the social media platform OurBytes where I also mentor several apprentice junior developers has given me an opportunity to sharpen my project management and teaching abilities coordinating meetings across global time zones and finding best solutions for productivity improvement. I am experienced in working directly with clients and writing applications with PHP like custom CMS or developing sites using WordPress, customized theming and plugins satisfying client needs by producing effective tools to improve business workflow. Still with me?

It is enjoyable working with what I know, however learning new technology is fun and as necessary is not an issue for me. (Insert sad face here) There are areas that I am not as experienced in as I would prefer like e-commerce, this is where you come in!

Currently the proud owner of many strengths, I consider weakness an opportunity to improve and I demonstrate leadership through my actions and integrity. I pride myself on my uncompromisingly unique and different perspective. Congratulations, if you are reading this you have passed phase one of the interview process.

Skills, Abilities, Roles

Languages, Frameworks, Libraries	HTML, HTML5, CSS, CSS3, SASS, JavaScript, ES6, ES5, XSS, XML, JSON, PHP, Python, Angular, ReactJS, React, Vue, Node, NodeJS, Nest, NestJS, TypeScript, TypeORM, WordPress, Express, Knex, Morgan, Cors, WebPack, Emotion, Storybook
Databases	MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Neo4J
Stacks	PERN, MERN, MEAN
Environments	LAMP, WAMP, XAMPP, Windows, Linux, Apple, AWS, Google Cloud, Netlify, Heroku, Vercel, Elementor, Docker, Kubernetes
Testing	Unit Testing, Smoke Testing, Mocha, Chai, Lighthouse, Jest, Enzyme, Supertest, Cypress
Roles	Software Engineer, Developer, Web Developer, Full Stack Developer, Backend Developer, Frontend Developer, UI Developer, UX Developer, Web Designer, Designer, Graphic Designer, Artist, Network Technician, Computer Technician, Music Producer, Video Producer
Miscellaneous	Web Applications, Web Development, Web FrameWorks, ECommerce, SEO, Software Planning, Software Architecture, Agile Development, Code, UI, UX, Frontend, Backend, API, JWT, Authentication, Error Logging, Error Reporting, Cross Browser Compatibility, Systems Administration, Animation, 3D Modeling, Graphics, Audio editing, Video editing, Digital Illustration, Illustration, Painting, Sculpture, Tattoo, unicycling
Interpersonal	Communication, Team Work, Ethical, Logical, Diligent, Learner, Resourceful, Analytical, Creative, Retention

Congratulations, you completed page one! Keep reading and I'll tell you a joke...

Experience

Convert (March 2021-Present)

Working at Convrrt has been an entirely challenging role that has been fast paced and exposed me to a software architecture and stack I had no previous experience with. This role is one I value because I constantly learn while performing my duties as an engineer, more than that I was given the opportunity to handle software integrations with tenant companies. This allows me to work with development teams from around the globe and tackle interesting and unique high priority issues for them.

- Primary duties include full stack software development in Vue, Javascript, TypeScript.
- Debugging in our code base, in the Google cloud and in our integrations with tenant software.
- Working with tenant company development teams to achieve positive outcomes.
- Ticket and bug tracking in a variety of software(s) such as Jira, Notion, Git

SizzWare Design and Development (January 2021-Present)

I started this company because I haven't been able to secure full time work in the industry, it consists of part time web development primarily focused around the WordPress platform. I hope to continue the company and provide work to aspiring developers as it grows.

- Primary duties include company marketing, sales, customer service, and website development.
- I discern client needs, supply possible options to meet those needs while maintaining client budget considerations.
- Developing client projects is more than just developing websites, considerations like digital marketing, SEO, and branding are part of the overall duties involved in achieving client satisfaction.
- Currently training junior developers in the WordPress platform and custom theming in order to outsource to them, providing industry experience, pay, and a valid reference to help them build a career.

Camas ACA Political Action Committee (February 2020-December 2020)

Wordpress based application built to provide information to the people of Camas WA so they might see the benefits of the proposed change in legislation on the next ballot at that time. Taking part in this project has allowed me to expand my technical abilities with the Wordpress platform, earning me valuable insights into developing for this platform which currently powers 39.5% of existing websites.

- Designed to allow users to read various studies advocating for and against medicinal and recreational marijuana.
- Utilizing Adobe Photoshop/Illustrator, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, theme modifications, and plugins to produce a basic informative website to serve content to citizens.

Freelance Developer and Artist (1998-Present)

This is a difficult section to compose because I have done so much during this time, I began as a graphic designer, moved into professional consulting for web design, blossomed into roles like art director and Sr. UI software engineer, even ran a couple of my own businesses. I have worked for many companies, in many industries during this time and been exposed to many environments.

- Designed and architected web applications to meet needs and provide marketable solutions to improve corporate growth through methodology like gamification, workflow improvement, and technical integrations and strategy.
- Deployed projects based on WordPress, PERN, and MERN stacks, that have been solo and in Agile team environments.
- WordPress theming & PHP, React frontends, Node and Nest backends, API creation and development, QA testing, accessibility testing
 as well as UI / UX development, graphic design, SEO and digital marketing.
- Sr. web developer for an SEO company way back in 2003 when SEO was simple...
- Built a prototype 3D model of a new type of steel production facility for a company called Black Smith Steel.
- Satisfied clients by producing works of art and design in the forms of illustration, logo development, portraiture, tattoo, and graphic design in many mediums such as; pencil, charcoal, ink, watercolor, mixed medium, 3D modeling, Adobe Creative Suite.
- Experience producing work for and with marketing, branding, product development, for both print and screen.

US Army - 91W Medic (Honorably discharged 2006)

After the dot com bubble decided to explode in a very unfortunate way, struggling to find work I wound up in retail, had student loans, a sick mother and no more career, I chose to go into the service in order to tackle these issues and provide myself another career path.

- Certified as an EMT B, received advanced battlefield medical training nearing a paramedic level.
- Stationed at Brooke Army Medical Center in San Antonio.
- Posted at the general surgery clinic, assisting in minor surgical procedures, patient care, managing over 1 million in sensitive medical equipment, while maintaining regular required service training and physical fitness standards.
- National Defense Service Medal, Global War on Terrorism Service Medal, Army Service Ribbon.

Page 2, Check! OK, I promised you a joke... What did the ocean say to the pirate?

Projects

OurBytes.net - Project founded to build a social media platform while solving inherent problems, and keeping social media human.

- Under my direction the initiative has grown to include a team of 10+ developers that I mentor and manage within the project, meanwhile the project is sustaining continued growth.
- Architecture and development is producing a viable MVP with a solid industry standard and error free code base.
- This also began as an academic exercise to learn new technology like Angular, TypeScript, and NestJS. Team growth has required
 me to learn and instruct others at a rapid pace, while project management needs have required me to seek productivity tools to aid in
 managing across time zones and countries.

FelonyDiscrimination.org - Web application developed to fight social injustice and affect real and quantifiable change in policy and legislation.

- Utilizing the PERN stack, I produced the MVP proof of concept in 2 weeks time.
- I am currently working on development of data scraping algorithms written in Python for database seeding, as my schedule permits.
- Moving forward at this point I am seeking funding for the organization in order to market it and build awareness of it, and its mission.

Education

2021+ I hope to complete certifications in Google cloud, personal training, maybe learn to bull ride, start a one class at a time approach towards a Phd in C.S.

- 2021 | Amazon Web Services Certified Developer (In Progress)
- 2021 | Harvard CS50 Introduction to Computer Science (In Progress)
- 2020 | FreeCodeCamp JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures (In Progress)
- 2021 | FreeCodeCamp Responsive Web Design Certification
- 2020 | THINKFUL Software Engineering Certification
- 2018 | Cisco Certified Entry Network Technician
- 2017 | CompTIA A+
- 2000 | Academy Of Art University

Volunteer

Certified Bice Ltd. - Jan 2020 - Present

- My organization adopted a bus stop This involves emptying the trash regularly, picking up the litter around that area.
- I am currently engaged in raising the funds to put in a new bus bench.

Denver Runners - March 2021 - Present

- I started this run club as motivation for myself and as a way to socialize and network, make friends and promote a healthy lifestyle.
- Currently 26 members strong, I have secured 2 sponsors for the club and offer monthly prize giveaways.
- My sponsorship benefits local businesses in the city of Denver through additional advertising and social media promotion that would otherwise not be affordable to smaller businesses. I am hoping to secure further sponsorship and expand events.

FelonyDiscrimination.org - Mar 2020 - Present

- Founded the organization.
- Built a web application that will serve as a voice and a resource to the people being discriminated against.
- The organization's purpose is to advocate for a change in policy and law as well as to collect data in order to fight the rampant discrimination against felons which only increases the recidivism rates nationally in the United States.

Hobbies

I tend to push myself and have a hard time keeping anything at a "hobby" level, that said I enjoy things like:

- Clowning. (I think you might have caught onto that by now)
- Gaming.
- Playing guitar, and writing music.
- Mentoring (Can you call that a hobby really? IDK)
- Credit building is a serious matter but I might be inclined to call it a hobby.
- My house plants, I finally defeated the gnats I picked up from a supermarket addition a little while back. (Pats self on back)
- Focusing on the little negative areas in life and processes in order to bring awareness and hopefully resolution to things that people otherwise just let fester and devolve until they impact them in a severe way. Optimism can be a thinking error!

You did it, I knew you could! Thank you!

Here's the punchline I promised: The ocean didn't say anything, it just waved...